Guide to the League for Industrial Democracy Records TAM.049
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Processed Records, 1921-1970
  - Farmer, James - Speaking Tour, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Farmer, James - Speaking Tour, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Finance, 1927-1928 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Finance, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Finance, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Finance, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Finance, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Finance, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Finance, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Finance, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Finance (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1927-1928 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Finance - Appeal for Funds (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Finance - Audit, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1950-1955 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Finance - Contributions, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Finance - Contributions (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Finance - Expense Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Finance - Form Letters, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Finance - Form Letters, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Finance - Form Letters, 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Finance - Form Letters, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Finance - Paid Bills, 1927-1928 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1927-1928 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Financial Reports, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Financial Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Financial Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Financial Reports, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Financial Reports, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Finance - Tax Exempt Status, 1930-1940 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Finance - Tax Exempt Status, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Flyers, 1922, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Fragments (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Fund for the Republic, 1957-1959 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Gabler Case, East Germany, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Haynes, 1927-1928 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Hertzberg, Sidney - Personal, 1957-1958 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - History of Socialist Thought, 1927-1928 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - International Association of Machinists, 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Democracy Foundation, 1924-1926 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Democracy Foundation, 1927-1928 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Institutes, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Institutes (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - IWW Subversion Case, 1927-1959 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Knight, Ralph Case, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Labor Age, 1927-1928 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1927-1928 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1950-1952 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Laidler, Harry (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Laidler, Harry - Biographical Material, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Laidler, Harry - Campaign for Alderman, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Laidler, Harry - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Laidler, Harry - Personal, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Laidler, Harry - Personal, 1957-1961 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Laidler, Harry - Personal - Books and Articles, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Laidler, Harry - Personal - Meetings and Lectures, 1950-1951 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Laidler, Harry - Personal - Speaking Tours, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Series, 1932-1933 (Box 26, Folder 6, Box Shared Tamiment 011, Folder 12)
  - Lecture Series, 1934 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Series, 1935-1936 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Series, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Series, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Series, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Series, 1941-1944 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Series - Form Letters, 1947-1949 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Series - Form Letters, 1950-1955 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Series - Form Letters, 1956-1957 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Series - Rand School, 1927-1928 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents, 1927-1928 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents, 1927-1928 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - L.I.D. Advances, 1951-1956 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Lucio, Filiberto (Anthony) USCG-NMU, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Membership, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Membership, 1927-1928 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Membership, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Membership, 1945-1949 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Membership, 1950-1951 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Membership, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Membership, 1957-1961 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Membership (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Membership Lists (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Membership Lists - Other Organizations (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Memos, 1927-1928 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Memos, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Memos (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Minutes - Administrative Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1924-1926 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1927-1928 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1929-1930 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1931-1932 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1933-1934 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1935-1936 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1937-1938 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1943-1944 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1945-1946 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1947-1948 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1953 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1957-1958 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Minutes - Board of Directors, 1964-1970 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Minutes - Executive Committee, 1958-1970 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Minutes - Labor Committee, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Minutes - Nominations Committee, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Minutes - Reorientation Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Modern Capitalism in the U.S., 1927-1928 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - National Office Forum, 1927-1928 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - New York Teachers Strike, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Notes, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Office Managment, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Office Managment, 1957-1958 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Office Managment, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Office Managment, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Office Managment, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Office Managment (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Officers, 1927-1928 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Officers, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Officers, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Pamphlet, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Pamphlet Preparation, 1927-1928 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlet Preparation, 1950-1951 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Pamphlet Preparation, 1952-1955 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Pamphlet Preparation - Form Letters, 1948-1949 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Pamphlet Preparation - Form Letters, 1950-1955 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Pamphlet Preparation - Form Letters, 1956-1957 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Patterson, Janet Case, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Pending Cases, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - People's Lobby, The, 1928 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - People's Lobby, The, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Perez-Varella, Juan and Manuel Alba Case - Clippings and Press Releases, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Perez-Varella, Juan and Manuel Alba Case - Correspondence and Private Bill Decision, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Perez-Varella, Juan and Manuel Alba Case - Senatorial Responses, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Planning, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Planning, 1927-1928 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Plasterers' Union Local 30, 1956-1958 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1924 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Press Releases, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases, 1950-1955 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1956-1959 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Press Releases, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Press Releases (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Printing, 1927-1928 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Programs, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Programs (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Proposed Study - Democratic Techniques Under Our Advancing Collectivism, 1943 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Publications, 1933 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Publications, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Publications, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Publications, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Publications, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Publications, 1953-1955 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Publications, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Publications (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Radio Programs, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Radio Programs, 1956-1960 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Radio Programs (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Rand School, 1950-1955 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Reid, Willie Extradition Case, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Report, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Research, 1927-1928 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Research, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Reservations, 1927-1928 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Resume, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Social Planning, 1931-1940 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Social Planning (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Songs, 1921-1940 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Southern Textile Survey, 1927-1928 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Speakers, 1927-1929 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Speakers, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Speakers, 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Speakers, 1952 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Speakers, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Speakers, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Speakers, 1957-1961 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Speakers - Coldwell, M.J., 1950-1951 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Speakers - Form Letters, 1951-1952 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Speakers - Form Letters, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Speakers - MacKenzie, Norman, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Speech Summaries, 1927-1928 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Stable Money Association, 1927-1928 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Starr, Mark - Lecture Tour, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Starr, Mark - Lecture Tour, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Starr, Mark - Lecture Tour, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Starr, Mark and Joseph Schlossberg Luncheon, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Students, 1922 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Students, 1959-1961 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Students (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Students - Activities, 1929-1930 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Students - Activities, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Students - Activities, 1950-1955 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Students - Activities, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Students - Colleges, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Students - Colleges, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Students - Colleges (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Students - Colleges - Requests, 1927-1928 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Students - Summer Institute, 1956-1957 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Students - Summer School, 1935-1937 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Students - Summer School, 1940-1941 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Students - Summer School (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Study Commissions, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Study Commissions, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Study Commissions, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Study Commissions - Replies to Questionaires, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Study Commissions - Replies to Questionaires, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Summer Institute for Social Progress, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Supplies, Orders, Contracts, 1927-1928 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Tangredi, Michael Case, 1958-1959 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Trip, Eastern, 1927-1928 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Trip, European, 1930-1938 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Trip, European, 1955-1957 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Trip, Middle Western, 1927-1928 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Trip, Middle Western (Return), 1927-1928 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Trip, New England, 1927-1928 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Trip, Pacific, 1927-1928 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Trip, Southern, 1927-1928 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Vanguard Press, 1927-1928 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Unemployment Insurance broadside, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 006, Folder 12)
  - Workers Defense League, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Workers Defense League, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 7)
- Series II: Addendum, 1947-1996
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist.
  This series is made up of materials, the bulk of which dates from the 1960s to the 1990s, generated by the League for Industrial Democracy. It contains articles; pamphlets; administrative, financial, and fundraising records; correspondence; research files; board of directors and executive committee minutes; membership files, files documenting their activities; and photographs. There is a significant amount of material documenting their annual conferences and institutes, including material related to their United States-wide Student-Labor Institutes. Some material relate to their solidarity campaigns with various unions on strike, including the American Federation of Teachers.
  - Box 38, 1969-1971
    This box contains materials from the Citizens Committee to Support General Electric (GE) Strikers including National Committee Members listings; newspaper ads, fundraising newspaper advertisement response cards, reports, budgets, and finances; correspondence, including correspondence with sponsors; post settlement reports; publicity; and other planning materials. The box also includes League for Industrial Democracy Detroit chapter correspondence; plannning materials and correspondence and a budget for the March for a Million School Children, sponsored by the Emergency City-Wide Committee for the Public Schools. There are grant proposals, planning materials, and grant rejection letters for a planned conference, entitled "Working for Democratic Change in the Americas" with the United States Youth Council. LID held another conference called "Campus Crisis, held at the Arden House. Materials on the conference include planning materials, correspondence, notes, and conference literature. There is also correspondence related to the Academic Committee of Correspodence, materials related to the Black Builders Work/Joint Apprenticeship program, planning materials on the New School for Social Research Labor Relations Luncheon Lectures in Spring 1971; and LID's "State of the Student Movement-1970" report with related correspondence.
  - Box 39, 1960-1979
    This box contains fundraising appeal correspondence, general correspondence, articles and other materials related to the League for Industrial Democracy in the 1960s and 1970s. Most notably, there is material from the Looking Forward article series. The issues in the series include, "From Protest to Politics: The Future of the Civil Rights Movement (Bayard Rustin), "The Failure of Urban Renewal" (Herbert J. Gans), "The Roots of the Dominican Crisis" (Theodore Draper), and "The Watts Manifesto and the McCone Report (Rustin). Michael Harrington's "Politics of Poverty pamphlet" and related correspondence are contained in this box, which also includes New York City LID Chapter Forum series materials, US delegation materials related to the 1973 Europe-America Conference; Citizens Committee for Justice for Farah Workers correspondence, pamphlets, planning materials; "The Ghetto" forum planning materials; LID reorganization materials; 69th Annual conference materials (1974); the Conference on National Economic Planning planning materials (1965-1966), the Poor People's Campaign: National Mobilization on June 19th, 1968; an annual report from 1973; the Black Power Debate forum in 1968; "Labor and International Affairs in the 70s" forum planning materials in 1972; and their work with the Frontlash Issues Workshop.
  - Box 40, 1960-1976
    This box contains pamphlets, LID's Journal, and LID News and Views. This box also contains loose meeting minutes, circulars, reports, and bulletins by the LID and other organizations.
  - Box 41, 1963-1978, 1989-1999
    This box contains loose materials, including board meeting and executive committee minutes, annual reports, circulars, luncheon materials, pamphlets, financial records, and other materials. The box also contains materials from the 1990s, including materials on the Bayard Rustin Fund; materials related to the Albanian Socialdemocratic Party deputy, Gaqo Apostoli; AFL-CIO donation to LID; International Participation Project materials; The Foreign Relations Bureau of the National Committee of the Independent Student Association (NZS) materials; materials documenting activities of LID from 1989-1990; Frontlash materials; Sandor Szilagyi fellowship; Daily News fundraiser; program summaries; campaign endorsements including to Yugoslavia demonstrations in 1992 and the arrest of Chakufwa Chihana; materials on the Child Labor Coalition; Romania training program; German Marshall Fund grant; United Mine Workers of America strike; Rustin Circle project; funding inquiries; circulars; and correspondence.
  - Box 42, 1965-1983
    This box contains subject files on civil disobedience, voter registration, miners, Mobilization for the Youth campaign, Metropolitan Urban Service Training (MUST), National Committee for an Effective Congress, National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, National Conference on Human Rights, National Council on Crime and Delinquency, National Conference on Citizenship, National Project on Ethnic America, Newark Community Union Project, Newark Defense Committee, Negro Poverty, negro and politics, negro education, nonviolence, Northern Student Movement, nuclear disarmament, Ohio Steering Committee for Adequate Welfare, Open Society, Organization of Organizations, Occupational Safety and Health Administration, Painters Union Project, Partners in Housing, Master Pax, Committee for Public education and Religious Liberty (PEARL), Pension Funds, planned communities, Planners for Equal Opportunity, political realignment, poltics and civil rights, polls and surveys, peace, poverty, poverty in cities, preferential treatment, progressive labor movement, race relations, radical right, Southern Christian Leadership Conference, Southern Regional Council, Citizens Coalition for an Adequate Education Budget, bombings, Block Development Project, the 20th Anniversary of the March on Washington, the Martin Luther King Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change, poor people campaigns in Mississippi, and the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party. The box also includes Harry Laider obituaries and eulogy and articles mentioning LID.
  - Box 43, 1964-1987
    This box contains subject files on the Southern Student Organizing Committee, spring mobilization, student politics, teamsters rank and file, Syracuse poverty program, Teachers Freedom Party, Norman Thomas, Triple Revolution, United Farm Workers, US Commission on Civil Rights, United Student Alliance, Urban School Crisis, Vienna Residents Labor Union, Voter Education Project, Watts (California) Riot, William Winpisinger, West Germany, Harvey Wheeler, the Workers Defense League, Civil Rights Bill, Community Development Agency, the Draft, DuBois clubs, Eldridge Cleaver Defense Committee, Emergency City-wide Committee for the Public Schools, the Fund for Peace, "Causes and Cures of Stagflation: A Tract for the 1980s" by Robert J. Alexander, Bermuda Conference, Jules Bernstein, Black Panther Party, Black Power, and Citizens Crusade Against Poverty. The box also has materials related to the Harrington, Rustin, Kemble speaking tour in 1964, their voter registration project, general correspondence, an unpublished draft of A Defense of Radical Liberalism by Arnold S. Kaufman, annual award meeting materials from 1965, luncheons and other speaking tour materials, public works debate, other debates and events.
  - Box 44, 1964-1970
    This box contains materials generated by the League of Industrial Democracy (LID). It includes Freedom Budget poverty campaign correspondence; Civil Rights Institute bills and materials; LID fund appeal bulletins; Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings from 1968-1969; 1967 Annual Conference journal, speakers, and other materials; "American Power in the 20th Century" pamphlet by Michael Harrington and related materials; Dissent subscription materials; Student Institute on the Democratic Left; "Who Speaks for the Consumer" pamphlet by Ralph Nader and related materials; School Crisis Meeting; LID and United Federation of Teachers (UFT) meetings; "Background Paper on the National Economy" for the Looking Forward series; New York City Youth Neighborhood Corps materials; LID Task Force on School Decentralization; 1969 Annual Conference journal and speakers; Public Employees Unionism conference proposals and other materials; and 1968 Annual Conference journal, speakers and other materials.
  - Box 45, 1965-1976
    This box contains files generated by the League of Industrial Democracy, including materials on the Frontlash training institute, including discussion materials, Washington trip; New York chapter minutes; "Accidental Century" insert in the New American; Dissent promotional materials; funding appeals; UC Berkeley meeting with LID; 1973-1976 annual conferences; Abraham D. Beame speech; New School urban problems lectures; Italian Student Labor Project proposal; administrative committee notes, integration lectures; clippings; youth vote conference; youth project materials, including finances, fundraising; Harry W. Laidler fellowship; land use, corporate power and public policy prospectus; Harrington v. Chafee complaint; United Federation of Teachers "Another Oceanhill-Brownsville?" article; "Urban School Crisis pamphlet draft; pamphlet promotional materials; UAW strike; magazines; Push Comes to Shove, by Steven Kelman materials; materials on Victor Alba and John Roche; and New York City crisis pamphlet materials.
  - Box 46, 1964-1972